<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Blog | Radnerus Suren</title>
    <link>https://radnerus.github.io/blog/blog/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Blog | Radnerus Suren</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 21:49:20 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://radnerus.github.io/blog/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>ஜல்லிக்கட்டு</title>
      <link>https://radnerus.github.io/blog/jallikattu</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 21:49:20 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radnerus.github.io/blog/jallikattu</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://radnerus.github.io/blog/img/kaalai.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kaalai&#34; /&gt;
As a kid growing up in Chennai, I literally don&amp;rsquo;t hear about this tradition all through the year, except on Maatu Pongal while flipping through channels I see a bull raging through in the TV. As many, I too wanted to know more about it. But it is postponed to this very day to dig up some facts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;origin&#34;&gt;Origin&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, the name Jallikattu is not the proper one, the original name of the game is &lt;strong&gt;YaeruThazhuval&lt;/strong&gt; (ஏறுதழுவல்) which means &lt;strong&gt;bull cuddling/holding&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Manju viratuthal&lt;/strong&gt; (மஞ்சு விரட்டுதல்), later it was changed to Jallikattu(சல்லிக்கட்டு/ஜல்லிக்கட்டு), which means &amp;ldquo;Jalli&amp;rdquo;+&amp;ldquo;Kattu&amp;rdquo;, which refers to the gold or silver coins which will be tied around the bull&amp;rsquo;s neck or on the horns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know bulls help a great deal in agriculture. But, they are so strong and even have the capacity to win over the lion, if a it is, all raged up. By this, the olden Tamil people, being as the brave Tamil lineage, to show their bravery they started a sport, which helps to show case a person&amp;rsquo;s bravery and strength and this was also a criteria for choosing a champion of the kingdom and its army. Also the Undefeated Bulls were the pride of the locality. Its like both the Honorable men in the army and the Bulls were treated equally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;rules-regulations&#34;&gt;Rules &amp;amp; Regulations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://radnerus.github.io/blog/img/kaalai-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kaalai&#34; /&gt;
Bulls are brought to the arena the previous day and tied in coconut groves around the village. Fodder is brought along and water is provided by the host villagers. Sometimes fodder is also provided. A team of veterinarians, animal welfare officials inspect the bulls and give a medical certificate. Before the event starts, they are lined up in batches of 15 close to the rear side of the vaadi vaasal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the temple bull of the host village has left the arena, each bull is taken into the vaadi vaasal, where Animal Welfare officers are present. The nose rope of the bull is cut and the bull is free to run. Young bulls and untrained ones participating for the first few times hesitate to leave the vaadi and are prodded by their owners. It is not easy to move them as they weigh anywhere between 250-350 kilos. The experienced bulls (which have long memories) are familiar with jallikattu events and offer their head to the owners to cut the rope. They plan their exit from the vaadi vaasal and time their jump to avoid the players. These are intelligent animals and have evolved in this environment over millennia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sport consists of holding on to the hump of the bull and running along with it for a given distance usually about 20-30 meters which is covered in barely 10-20 seconds. Although a few hundred players are present in the arena, only 2-3 attempt to get close to the bull and only 1 has a shot at grabbing the hump. Everything happens so fast that most players hit the dirt and the bulls go free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After leaving the arena, they go to a barricaded collection area of about 44,000 sq. ft. where experienced herders await the owners. Owners follow the bulls from the vaadi into the collection arena, this takes about 5-10 minutes. Once they enter, the herders help the owners rope in the bulls and take them out of the collection arena. 1-2 bulls will refuse to be roped and charge at everyone, some of them jump out of the collection area and make a run for it. Most of them head in the direction of their villages. There is the occasional injury due to the bulls not being roped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;current-trend&#34;&gt;Current Trend&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering we were the people who ranked our military with their skill against the Bulls and treat them as Gods, we are the World&amp;rsquo;s largest exporter of Beef (&lt;a href=&#34;http://beef2live.com/story-world-beef-exports-ranking-countries-0-106903&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;). There were 130 or so cattle breeds in India 100 years ago and now there are only 37. Unless we engage with the traditional livestock keepers and support them, we will lose these breeds as well as lay the ground for commercial cattle based dairies and slaughter houses to dominate the country&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tamil Nadu had six cattle breeds earlier and now we have lost the Alambadi breed. The remaining breeds are Kangayam, Pulikulam, Umbalachery, Barugur and Malai Maadu. There are a few more minor breeds without proper documentation or care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-ban-will-be-fatal&#34;&gt;A Ban will be Fatal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the Convention on Biological Diversity and heritage status practices worldwide, it is customary that these ancient traditional practices are left as they are but with rules to organise and regulate them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If jallikattu is banned, livestock keepers will be forced to abandon the raising of native livestock, which already stands threatened due to the extensive use of motor pumps, tractors and mechanised agriculture. If the sport is banned, it would be the death knell of native cattle species in Tamil Nadu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will not only lose our breeds but also our self-sufficiency in milk production as well as promotion of organic farming. If we lose our breeds and import foreign breeds, multinational commercial companies will dominate the dairy industry in India. The livelihood of millions in rural India is at stake here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People who want a ban on jallikattu are far removed from village life and do not know how this chain works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court and the Government of India needs to look at the big picture behind jallikattu. The Convention on Biological Diversity (CBD) supports traditional practices to keep the chain intact and thus enable conservation of native breeds. As an ancient nation with an ancient practice going back millennia, jallikattu should be preserved. There is no torture of any animal of any sort that takes place during the sport and the evidence of this can be seen from live media telecasts. The time a bull spends engaged in the sport is less than 30 seconds. If required, rules can be implemented to enhance the safety of the animals and men if required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India has already lost many cattle breeds and it can’t afford to lose any more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rather than banning this event! It would be great great to lay norms and monitor them! Let the Tradition and Our Friends prosper!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leader - The making!</title>
      <link>https://radnerus.github.io/blog/captaindhoni</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 15:50:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radnerus.github.io/blog/captaindhoni</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://radnerus.github.io/blog/img/dhoni.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Dhoni&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December 23, 2004&lt;/strong&gt;, still I remember the day when a man with long hair came to the crease, who made me feel sorry for him, after being runout for a duck in his ODI debut. That was the time when many like me wanted a stable wicketkeeper for our team! I was praying him to be the one. He was much more than I ever imagined him 😎. Then came the knock against Pakistan, that magnificent 148 - thanks to DADA for the belief! There started a new reign in Indian Cricket. Then the Duo joined Dhoni - Yuvi and literally chased everything! Those days were glorious ❤️.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-beginning&#34;&gt;The Beginning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Squad for WC 2007 T20i squad announced, I was literally broken down to find Jammy and Sachin not in it. I decided not watch the matches as my heros weren&amp;rsquo;t selected😒. Damn! cable operators discovered my thoughts. First match between Ind vs Pak wasn&amp;rsquo;t telecasted. I remember the day, I was sent for an errand by mom and I stood in front of a TV showroom watching Indian wickets tremble. Damn you, Asif!😡&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I returned home stone hearted, cursing the selectors. The next morning I woke up to see my captain raise. That day I flipped through all news channels, to see the bowl out, literally spend the whole day watching it over and over again. That WC was full of moments. We were under-dogs throughout, even though we reached the finals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://radnerus.github.io/blog/img/dhoni-wc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Dhoni&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-glory&#34;&gt;The Glory&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 24, 2007&lt;/strong&gt;, It was the day of finals. Myself with a few friends, bunked our tuitions and we were glued to TV hours before the start. That was a rollercoaster ride😍! Gautham hitting one of his best knocks, Misbah&amp;rsquo;s brilliant stand, Umar&amp;rsquo;s quick fire knock, etc., But everything came down to &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Experts would have told to me to go with the lead spinner. But, I had other ideas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came the Might CSK, glorified by Dhoni. Succeeded Jammy and Jumbo as ODI and Test captain respectively. No. 1 Test team, ODI World Cup and almost won all the major trophies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-captain&#34;&gt;The Captain&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never intend to say Dhoni is the best Batsman, Finisher, Keeper nor he is the wisest of the lot. But the package he provides, none could afford. &lt;strong&gt;We need a trustworthy Keeper, he entered scene! We need a winning captain, he stepped forward! We wished for more trophies, he granted them! Finally we find a more aggressive one, He steps aside.&lt;/strong&gt; This is Dhoni for you - The Captain I Love! ❤️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year! A New Start!</title>
      <link>https://radnerus.github.io/blog/newyear2016</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 19:04:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://radnerus.github.io/blog/newyear2016</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://radnerus.github.io/blog/img/new-year.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;New Year&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2016-a-hero-a-villan&#34;&gt;2016 A Hero &amp;amp; A Villan&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, the year started with its own set of twists and turns 😉. All the expectations that I had towards the year were crushed in the first few months one after the other. After all my expectations crushed, I should have stopped there. But I had other ideas, I thought of rising up from the ashes like a &lt;strong&gt;Phoenix&lt;/strong&gt;😎. Its wasn&amp;rsquo;t long, before the Phoenix was kicked to the place it came from 😑. The worst thing about the Phoenix was it tried to work solo, barring all social connections. With the Phoenix, I lost myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, there came a bunch of people who change the way everything were! People from unexpected places. Some looked me up for what I&amp;rsquo;m 😄. Some kicked me for what I&amp;rsquo;m not 😫. Both made me to be what I&amp;rsquo;m today. All those expectations which was turned to disappointments, created opportunities. Now I realize that those opportunities were worth the disappointments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Damn Phoenix&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, I made a few irreparable damages. Hope those damages will be fruitful for them! &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Breaking down is Good! Getting up is Better! Going on will lead you towards being the Best!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the new opportunities there comes a lot more responsibilities. Embrace the Pain and Loss. For the past few days, I have been thinking of the accomplishing my expectation of 2016 in 2017. Improving my communication skill is one such thing! Writing this blog is towards that. A small step towards my goals 😊.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I thank all those People who made me stronger and made me realize who I&amp;rsquo;m. Sorry for all the damages caused by me intentionally or accidentally.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size=&#34;2&#34;&gt;*This is my first attempt in blogging. Please let me know if you find any improvements.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>